Markets, speculation, and risk. This is
the Chat with Traders podcast.
Welcome to Chat with Traders, episode
306. I'm Tessa, your co-host, and today
we have a special episode. We're diving
into a topic that has really captured
the attention of traders in recent
years, prop firms. Now, I'm not talking
about the traditional brickandmortar
firms that first made waves in the early
2000s. I'm talking about a newer
generation, the online funding prop
firms that began to surface around 2015
and really gained momentum during the co
era and still growing. Since Trade the
Pool, one of these prop firms, has been
a longtime sponsor supporter of the
podcast, we thought it would be the
perfect opportunity to bring on their
CEO, Michael Katz. In this conversation,
I'll be asking him some of the big
questions that traders, myself included,
have been curious about. Now, whether
you use these prop firms or not, whether
you like them or not, we hope you can at
least keep an open mind for this
episode. I am a developing trader like
many of you and am constantly trying to
learn and grow as a trader and find ways
to help me in my trading journey and
share them with you. So to be clear, the
main purpose of this episode is not
about promoting prop firms. Instead,
it's about pulling back the curtain and
gaining a better understanding of how
these firms operate. Well, at least from
Trade the Pool's perspective, what they
mean for traders and the questions that
often surround them. So, we hope you
enjoy this episode and learn something
from it. Let's dive right in. Ladies and
gentlemen, we're so pleased to introduce
Michael Katz from Trade the Pool.
Hey, Michael. Welcome to Chat with
Traders.
>> Thanks so much. Thanks for having me.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's great having you on the show
finally. And so your background, did you
actually initially come from the
brickandmortar prop firm type of
environment or
>> Yeah. Yeah, for sure. Um, you know, I've
been trading for 17 years in total. Um,
mostly stocks and futures and after a
good few years of battling and
succeeding, I became the head of the
traders in one of the local uh shops
here. and and then from there I moved to
actually building trade the pool.
>> Yeah. And and trade the pool is
associated with the fibers.
>> That's correct. Yeah. It's um our parent
company um so when Gil the founder
reached out and he found me through
friends he reached out told me about it.
I said I'm your guy. give me the keys
and I'll do that and uh the rest is
history.
>> Yeah. So the fivers were f are focused
on forex and trade the pool is focused
on US stocks equities.
>> Yeah. So so fers is related to CFDs. So
that's uh forex and also commodities
indices as well. But on the CFD side, um
established from 2016,
probably the best um at least in at the
top three company in the in the industry
of the prop industry and trader pool. We
launched it as I said three years ago uh
focusing on equities mostly US stocks or
at least currently US stocks and um but
we will surely expand soon to uh to
Europe and also Asia.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. So I was going to ask you
about that. Yeah cuz I remember you
telling me that it was initially just
open to to US traders.
>> I mean it's not for just US traders. I
mean the the equity is like you can
trade US markets but uh but you can come
from anywhere in the world. We have
traders from literally every place in
the world. Most of them are in the state
just because
>> the connection between the stock market
and to um North Americans like US and
Canada but uh but we have guys from
India and and Japan and Brazil
everywhere in the world. Yeah. And then
Trey the Pool is based where?
>> So we're located in Israel like 20
minutes from Tel A Viv. Uh that's the
headquarter. But um we got roughly 80 to
100 guys all across the world. A lot of
them are in are in the US. the guys that
operating in uh the YouTube um live
stream that that we host every day and
um support team discord all of that uh
handled by mostly by us guys.
>> Yeah. So it seems like there are less
and less brickandmortar type of prop
firms and there's just more a trend of
more online funding type of prop firms.
Sometimes I get confused between saying,
you know, like the regular prop firms
and the online funding prop firms. So I
think maybe it's easier if I just say
funding prop firms for the kind of the
new prop firms rather than
>> that way we don't get confused. Um yeah.
So
what do you think is the key kind of
attraction to these funding prop firms?
>> Right. So, it's just an evolution,
right? In the early 2000 or even a
little bit before that, the internet
came out, you could trade from um your
home, right? Or call your broker or do a
lot of the stuff that you couldn't do, a
lot of the stuff that you could do
today. It's just an evolution in the
opportunities that the vendor or the or
the companies provide to the retail
traders, right? So, at first you would
call your broker, then you uh was able
to place orders you yeah place orders
through your computer. Then commission
free trading that shift the industry
completely and made all brokers to allow
commission free trading. something that
never been done before. And I guess the
the next step in that evolution is
actually us as as the prop that we give
everyone
an opportunity, everyone in the world an
opportunity to actually enter the
market. Um pay a super small fee like
literally limit your risk in trading,
right? instead of going and putting your
hard work and money uh into the test in
most cases lose it and not not having
enough capital to trade with. So those
all all those actually shift into toward
the the prop solution uh which is
limiting your risk giving you enough
capital that actually worth your time.
You know I remember and you probably um
will feel the same. I remember when when
I first started to trade, I spent hours
on hours and at the end of the month, I
made $200, $500, right? Nothing that
actually compared to the time that I
invested in actually learning and and
clicking the mouse key. Do you relate to
that?
>> Oh, yeah. Yes, of course.
>> Yeah. So, so nowadays I can I can take
much bigger account, spend the same time
and actually make more money. So, so it
just makes sense.
>> Yeah. The key attraction I know for me
and I can say this on behalf of many
traders is the the access to large size
capital that you you know that most
traders um would just dream of having
years ago, you know. Um and then the
leverage, you know, the leverage on
this, um it's just really unheard of.
It's it's really a a very unique
opportunity that traders have access to
these days.
>> Yeah. and and the fact that with let's
say even $50 or $100 like you said you
can trade enough capital that worth your
time and and can make you money while
you're just risking that fee for example
and and we will probably talk about it
in a second but even if I'm trying the
what we call the valuation the test that
the challenge that we give you in order
to give you a funded account even if you
do that five times You failed four
times, right? And on the fifth time you
pass, you paid $500
and you actually and and that's the
risk. That's it. You're done. Anything
that you do from here is either make
money and take some home or or lose the
account, of course, but at the end of
the day, it's not your money that you're
risking besides those uh evaluation
fees. It it almost makes it feel like
it's just a no-brainer to go this route
rather than trade your own personal
account and risking so much more your
hard-earned savings or whatever. You
know, even maybe some people taking
their retirement um money out to to try
to trade and then when it's gone, it's
gone. You know, it's so hard to build it
back up. Whereas with um going through
the prop trading, you know, funding
route, yeah, like you said, the most you
can lose, that's your risk is the
evaluation fees that you pay to have a
chance to trade a large capital um or
whatever capital size that you're aiming
for. Um, so it seems like a no-brainer,
but then there are kind of
misconceptions around trading with prop
firm. And some of them are negative
misconceptions or maybe they're not
misconceptions. Maybe they are really,
you know, valid from, you know, a
certain traitor's point of view. An
example is that one of the things that
we have um heard over time is that
around the rules for example um the
tough rules that most online prop firms
business model is based on you know
traders you know they survive based on
traders failing the challenges
>> in order to take that revenue to pay out
those that pass them And so some people
equate this to like a casino model.
>> Uh what are your thoughts on that?
>> Yeah, that's a good topic to to cover, I
guess, because this is something that a
lot of the traders are talking about
these days and ask themselves. So first
of all, as I see it and as at least we
operate on the Fiverrs on a trader pool
is, you know, a business doesn't have to
have um one route of um income, right?
And that's one thing that you always I
guess as a business doesn't matter if
it's for finance business or or a
restaurant, right? you're looking to
have a few streams of income and and
that way when something is u not going
well on one direction you have enough
capital on the side uh to back it or or
another stream uh to help you with that.
So, of course, there are the fees that
the traders pay for, and I'll touch that
about that in a second. And of course,
there are the tra there is the trading
part when when we execute the traders,
the good traders, we take them to the
market. Um, but that's trading, not
every time it will work. And there are
many other streams that we're either
working on or already established. Um
for example uh we developing um trading
journal uh we have uh trade ideas
section we have education section so we
always working on not just on the
funding part but actually a full
ecosystem uh that will be involved
around this and that will give us two
things one another stream of income this
the second thing supporting our traders
and and regarding the
so That's on on trade a pool on how we
do that. regarding what I wanted to say
about the the evaluation fee
specifically on trade pool because we're
equity uh company
or focusing on on the US market the fees
like our fees are much higher not
talking about the valuation I'm talking
about like what we pay the expenses are
much higher than for example what used
to think of um you know in the forex
industry right in the forex industry you
just take a feed CFD feed cost a few
thousands and that's it. In our case, we
have uh the license to the exchanges,
the the feed from the exchanges, the
level one and level two and the vendor
and the trading platform. There are so
many expenses around that and the fees
of the evaluation covers some of that.
Yeah. Well, that's that's great to hear
to kind of give a so we can hear the
perspective from the company's side on
what those expenses are. I feel like
trade the pool is being an advocate for
traders by offering education. I I've
seen a change in the last few years that
you have built more of a community um
based platform and and education to
encourage traders to to continue
developing. Um I think that's great.
Thanks. That's uh this is something that
actually uh Gil the founder uh brought
from day one to the Fiverrs and of
course I led it um on the trader pool
side which the idea is Gil background is
basically a forex trader. So, so our
idea is, you know, we are we are our
traders, right? We know exactly what our
traders need in order to uh progress, in
order to push themselves for further
more and to become better traders. So
education is by far the key element that
we're using besides technology and and
other instruments but just give the
traders as much information as they as
we can to provide. So we're doing live
streams every single day trading
together. We're doing events um risk
management events and strategies. We
build ebooks. Um, we have a VOD section
with more than 150 videos. I'm
interviewing, as you know, I'm I'm
interviewing our funded traders. So,
every time someone is passing the
evaluation,
I go um and interview him, ask him about
the evaluation, about his trading, and
they all share the information, and you
can hear about it and see it, and then
uh you learn and adjust and uh become
better.
>> Yeah. and we'll get into the the stats a
little bit on your traders. Um, but I I
think that's awesome. And about the
traders that do well, can you touch on a
little bit more? Do they This is a
simulated account. When when traders are
trading in the evaluation and also the
funded phase, they're always trading in
a simulated um environment. Is that
correct?
>> Not always. Uh on the evaluation, it's a
simulator account. Yes. on the funded on
the funded phase we choose which account
to create as as um a real account real
market conditions
>> and also not just the account but also
the orders itself. So basically on our
risk team we have what we call profiles.
>> Mhm. And once you trade on your
evaluation and with your K KYC and your
trading activity, we categorize you, put
you in a profile. For example, um um you
know, with we categorize the risk
tolerance, um the asset you're trading,
uh the days, the number of trades,
everything that we can get around
basically and put you in a profile. Once
we understand that you fit a certain
profile, in most cases we will know if
we can take you to the market or not the
the account and also orders that will
come through. So for example, if you're
buying 100 shares of Apple, we might not
take you to the market, but if you're
buying 100 shares of Tesla, we might do
that as well. U so we analyzed in the
profile while analyzing the the market
conditions in general. So there are
traders on a funded that will stay on
the simulator account and there are
traders and orders that will go to the
live market.
>> Oh, so I didn't know that. I just heard
that in general like the prop firms,
they always, you know, even the funded
traders, they'll always be on like a
simulated account and um that the
company will never copy their trades or
anything like that. But it sounds like
that's not the case with trade the pool.
You do pick and choose traders that you
think um you want to take on, you know,
to copy their trades and and replicate
that in the live account. Is that
correct? Is that how I'm understanding
it?
>> Exactly. That's uh what we call Cbook.
So you have a book if you go directly to
the market the whole time or book if you
stay uh stay in house or Cbook when it's
an hybrid. Basically, we do that same
thing on the Fiverr, same thing on
trader pool. Um, it's not an easy task,
one of the one of the hardest even
because the work behind it is is a very
uh unique one and and takes a lot of
analysis and data gathering and and our
guys on the risk need to be on their
toes. But but it is Yeah.
>> Wow. Okay. Well, let's get into um some
of the the numbers a little bit just to
give me and the listeners an idea of
your traders. For example, what's the
percentage of traders that passed the
evaluation? Let's start with that.
>> Okay, first of all, I'm super proud of
the number. Obviously, I would love to
to see more of that, but we but we are
at around 20 to 25%.
>> Which is, you know, comparing to trading
by yourself on on your own account,
which it's roughly two or 5%. So, um, so
I'm excited about those numbers. And it
makes sense again if you if you're not
trading your capital, if you have enough
capital and you're not trading your
capital, you're not risking your money,
that means that your mind can shift from
uh attaching the money to your decision
making to detaching the money from it.
And and once you do that, you can make
uh logical decisions.
Um and once you have enough capital to
work with, you can get into a few trades
simultaneously. You can take the right
number of share and the right uh risk
reward kind of thing. So, so it makes
sense that you're and obviously the
stress is much lower when you're not
trading your capital. So, it makes sense
that the the numbers are high.
Obviously, I would prefer to see more,
but these are roughly
>> I think that's pretty high. 22 25ers.
That's that's really encouraging. And
can I ask you more that what's the
average number of times an average
trader fails an evaluation before they
actually pass?
>> Before they actually pass, it's between
three to five attempts
>> before you pass. Yeah. And this is
something that I'm happy to speak about.
I speak about it on our funded traders
interviews as well all the time. I share
the information because I think first of
all first of all it's a great number to
have nothing to be ashamed of. It's
great. Someone most guys need that those
three to five attempts just to get a get
the understanding of the rules and the
platform and really um get the idea or
the shift in their mind about what it's
what it likes to trade on a simulator
with someone else capital behind it
basically. uh so you just take that time
and also I think it's important that
everyone all the traders will understand
that you know um you got to understand
that you shift in many guys shift their
strategy or tweaked it in order to fit
the rules because when you're trading
your own capital you're trading with a
broker you're trading with no rules
right
>> no one will tell you okay you're done
for the day that's it daily pause right
there there is no such on your broker
account. So, so now that you have that,
you need to understand how you work with
it.
>> And
>> yeah, I I can tell you that 99% of our
funded traders will say exactly this.
When you have boundaries, and this is
kind of a weird thought at first, but
when you add boundaries to your trading,
when you add them, you actually become a
better trader.
That's incredible to see
>> these rules. A lot of um I don't know if
I should say a lot. I don't I can't
quantify how many, but we, you know, we
just hear things like, you know, people
complaining about the rules of the prop
firms. I mean, every prop firm is
different and have their own rules and
they need to really um really understand
those rules and read the fine prints and
really understand it. And um I I have to
admit that um you know me, I I I I have
bought some evaluations and I'm just
going to be very transparent. I um have
failed several around the range that you
were talking about the average trader.
So I'm pretty average I guess. And um so
I have failed a handful of times. And um
part of that is just getting used to the
platform and then getting used to the
rules and and kind of adjusting the way
that you normally would trade um because
it's completely different like you said.
Um you know when you're trading on your
own especially when you're a de
developing trader and you know and
you're still kind of getting experience
and stuff like that. You're still
working alone and you don't really have
anyone to hold you accountable and have
rules for you. And yeah, you may develop
rules for yourself, but maybe it's not
um just not good enough to to help you
become a better trader. And so
>> when I first started with uh trade the
pool um going through the evaluation, I
was really mad because I was like, you
know, this is so unreasonable. And what
was the a max draw down daily draw down?
I forgot what was that like 1% or 2%.
>> Uh depends on which account. Yeah. And I
guess it was on on our previous uh
programs, right? We we actually launched
the last five months or so, six months.
>> Yeah. But whatever it was, it was quite
small compared to what we're used to
when we're trading on our own because we
could kind of let kind of let things
we're more flexible whereas you cannot
be as flexible. And then there were
times when I um you know was uh kind of
on tilt and I wanted to revenge trade
and I and I did and then I got um I got
kicked out you know from the what is it
called? The daily loss.
>> The daily pause. Daily pause.
>> Daily pause. That's a nice word to say.
Daily pause. So
>> because it's it is stopping you for the
day. Not
>> Yeah. It stopped me for the day. And I
was so mad and and I was like, you know
what? After a while, after several um
evaluations, I kind of got used to it.
I'm like, you know, imagine me doing
this on my own, like, you know, my own
personal account,
>> how much more money I would lose trading
on Tilt and and trading emotionally in
the uh evaluation.
>> Yes, it's it's annoying, but you know,
it's going to help you to to just follow
the rules.
Exactly. I mean, it's like having a
seatelt on. Wear your seat belt.
>> And and that's that's the thing about
trading within those boundaries. You you
want your trading to be you know this
sentence when when everyone is saying
you want your trading to be boring,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> So, so that's the same thing. You want
your trading to be within boundaries.
When when you have rules, you you
actually
you're you're increasing your chances to
succeed automatically because you can
you're not losing more than you should.
You're not um going in looking for that
home run trades, right? You're doing it
consistently. You're building yourself
as a trader, developing yourself.
>> Yeah. But let me ask you, let me ask you
something else that you know for the
traders that let's say without the prop
firms um the ones that do really well um
you know like on their own like trading
on their own uh their own account their
own capital
>> um and you know seasoned traders and
then they come let's say because you
know we know that some of them still go
through these prop firms because hey
it's it's extra why not you know it's
like extra leverage and stuff like Yeah.
And then they go through them and it's a
completely different could be a
completely different world for them
because
they may not have the same set of rules
even though their rules are different.
It you know they can still trade
successfully with different rules.
coming over to a prop firm like trade
the pool with these rules
>> would that force them to that would they
may not do well in in this environment
is what what are your thoughts?
>> Yeah. So obviously we have also pro
traders uh trading with us. Um you know
guys that been in the market for 15
years even 20 years uh been killing it
and and they do need to adjust their um
their strategies, their setup, the the
way they react, the risk management uh
to our conditions. Um some of them found
success and and you know did those
tweaking and and made it happen. Some
said you know what I'm good with my
capital and continue to trade on their
own money and I think what the
difference what what we do and you know
professional traders are roughly two 3%
in the world right and the other traders
are just um struggling or somewhere
along the learning curve of trading and
trying to make it and and I think what
we do and also see that on the numbers
is we take that learning curve and make
it much more shorter. Right? if you need
when I started I needed to spend two
years or three years in order to learn
and until I found some profitability
um we have guys or also ladies uh Morgan
for example I did an interview with her
it's online and and she passed the
evaluation after six months of trading
like she just literally just started to
trade and she passed the evaluation and
a few months after I did another
interview with her uh about her payout,
right? So,
>> so that's insane. I mean, to change,
we're literally changing the way traders
uh trade and that's incredible to be
part of that.
>> Yeah, that's amazing. And continuing on
with the stats. So once traders pass and
they get funded for the first time,
>> what are your numbers on the percentage
that fail once they got funded the first
time? Because that's another phase. It's
like true, you know, it has a different
psychology, don't you think? Because
it's like, oh, now I'm funded.
>> 100%. That's a that's a very good one.
Very good topic to to cover. Um first of
all, yeah it is a second phase and and
the thing about the funded phase is that
on one end you have the guys that are
all in. They just want to make money,
right? Just want to get to that payout
phase super fast. They will uh change
their strategy completely. They will go
all in. they will risk much more than on
the evaluation really changing
completely what they did and and then
obviously they will blow up because if
you're changing everything and risking
too much you will lose your account and
then you have the guys that says uh you
know what I they they will say I just
got to that funded phase after a few
attempts finally got to that funded
phase right and they will take it super
slow consistent and they will get to the
payout. They will instead of risking
let's say on the evaluation they risk
$200 per trade, they will risk $100 per
trade. Instead of taking 3,000 shares,
they will take a,000 shares. they will
automatically lower the risk, take their
time and those guys um in most cases
will make uh the way to the profit to
the payout and also be with us much
longer time than those that will you
know just try to eat.
Would you recommend
that um say during your evaluation
phase, should you trade in your
evaluation
phase the way that you would trade when
you get funded so that it's consistent
and you actually get more practice?
Because during the evaluation phase,
that time, let's just say takes two,
three months to to pass depending on on
your skills. And why not, like this is
how I'm thinking, like why not, you
know, trade the way you really would
once you're funded from the start, even
though it might take long and and trade
trade conservatively.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, and then, you know, make
tweaks and there's a lot you can learn
from that. And then once you're funded,
you continue to be that same trader.
continue to trade the way you traded
during your evaluation rather than like
you mentioned earlier some like just go
all in or you know do whatever to just
get funded really fast and once they get
funded they start trading like like a
different personality like another way I
mean shouldn't we just trade the
evaluation like we really would trade
>> yeah that's for sure and and that will
help us as a company for on our risk
management side as well if we got to
know you on the evaluation and we see
that you still continue doing the same
thing on your funded, it will be much
more easier for us to manage the risk
behind the scene. And and of course for
the trader, if you already proved
yourself on the evaluation and you and
you show that you can make it the way
you did, then of course it makes sense
to continue to do the same thing. Be
boring about it and uh and be
consistent. That's the key.
>> Yeah. So once they get funded for the
first time, what is the percentage of
your traders fail that funding?
>> So fail that funding. It's roughly we
basically have 15% that that will hold
their hold their account after that. So
85. Yeah.
>> Okay. Okay. Got it. Yeah. I mean it's
hard. Trading is hard.
>> Trading is hard. uh easier when it's not
your own capital because you know even
if um I just interviewed like literally
an hour ago I interviewed uh Mark he's
been with us uh roughly a year and a
half he got four funded accounts and
this is his fourth funded account
basically
>> and he lost the first the first three
right he reached the payout and all but
he still uh blew the account blew the
account because um Sometimes
you cross those boundaries and and those
rules and you know whatever that comes
in mind when you when you're trading
like the psychology of it and you lose
the account. But but once you proved
yourself and and this I say a lot once
you proved yourself that you can pass
the evaluation it's much easier for you
to go back again and pass the evaluation
again and get funded.
>> Yeah.
>> It took him one day to pass.
>> Wow. because he already did it a couple
of times.
>> Now share with you us what you see in
the patterns and and characteristics of
those traders that end up staying longer
with trade the pool being funded several
times and and not just the first time
but you know they they at least two or
three times. What are the common themes?
What what do you see that you can share
with us?
Yeah. So the guys that that are sticking
to their accounts are first of all they
build a cushion and then we got Arbnor
and and Michael Tarantula that spoke
about it in their interviews. They they
come when they start to trade on the
funded account they like I said before
they start super slow. they build a
cushion and then they start to increase
the sizes and the risk because you have
something to to fall back uh on right
to. So that's the first thing you need
to do on your funded account. You start
slow building a cushion. Once you build
that enough uh capital to to fall back
on, then you can start increasing your
sizes. And second thing it's scaling
into the account right of course scaling
out as well but most importantly scaling
in. If you go um into a trade full power
you know risking all the capital all the
all the dollar you're willing to lose on
a trade. Even if it's let's say you
you're willing to lose $100 instead of
clicking the mouse key and then put the
full $100 at risk. Start by putting $10
at risk $20, right? you scale, you build
the position. Once you accumulate the
position, you can actually see first of
all a much higher success rate. It will
give you more flexibility of managing
that trade because even if the trade
goes against you, it's nothing. You're
still risking $10 out of the 100 and and
that give you confidence at the end of
the day on your trades.
>> Yeah. what you described requires a lot
of patience and a lot of um you know
following your your process and and and
patience and dedication to it and not
being in a hurry. I think that's the key
is the patience part.
>> Yeah. I mean the market will be open
tomorrow as well, right? You don't need
to look for that uh big trade just to to
make it. Although we do have some
traders like this. Uh just today I spoke
with the uh Jim. He made $85,000 on one
trade. Uh PTHL, I don't know if you saw
this chart, but it went from $30 to $1
and a Chinese company.
>> Yeah.
>> And it was incredible. But if you look
at the other trades that he made, it
wasn't to be honest, it wasn't that
good. Then I spoke with him today and I
told him, "Listen,
we want you to start building it as and
trade consistently and not looking for
that crazy move from out of nowhere like
a black swan of the company."
>> This leads me to what those traders that
um that you know have been funded
several times, what are they actually
mostly trading? Uh is it penny stocks or
small cap, large cap, ETFs?
>> Yeah, we we do have a variety of uh
traders. Uh we offer 12,000 symbols. Um
so stocks and ETFs. Um most of our
traders because there are young guys
that would love to um mostly short and
trade penny stocks, small caps, they
will definitely do that. And because we
also don't have a locate fee and
borrowing fee of all kind uh they really
enjoy that and and will come to us. So
you can short any small cap, any penny
stocks uh on our platform. And um but
besides that, we do have guys like like
I just mentioned Mark um that I
interviewed
hour an hour ago and he's I'm guessing
by his face is about 70 75 years old
around those lines.
>> Uh he's been in the market for like 40
years. great interview and and he's been
trading just one ticker actually two
tickers the entire evaluation he traded
SMCI and Lemonade that's it the full
evaluation he did those two just
learning the learning the nuances of the
of the tickers and then he understand
more about the price action the momentum
everything involved around it so it
really depends on your personal ity, but
a lot of our guys are small cap trader.
>> That's why I love that you offer stocks
because there's just so many
opportunities,
>> you know, like 12,000 symbols, ETFs or
whatever, however you want to trade.
It's it's amazing. Um h have any traders
ever been denied a payout?
>> Yes.
>> And not because we um decided to just
because of that, but actually because he
broke the rules. We do have the rules
that you got to follow. Uh one of them
will be not trading before the halt for
example. So if a stock made a um a move
of 8% within four minutes and we know
that u whenever it does 10% within five
minutes it's automatically altered. Then
if he traded like this and broke the
rule then we eventually will invalid the
trade. Um,
so as long as but as long as you're in
the parameters and the objectives that
we set beforehand, you're good to go.
Doesn't matter if you will make $85,000
on a single trade like I just mentioned.
I mean, that's a it's not a great trade.
It wasn't, you know, on a technical
level, support, resistance, reversal,
whatever it is, it took a trade. It took
a shot basically. Um, and he made that
money, so we will pay that. He didn't
break any rules, uh, Jim, on the 85k.
But if you did break the rule, even if
it's $2,000, obviously, we won't pay
that for sure. Uh, this is why, as you
mentioned before, you got to read the
rules before. We we put them
>> straight forward on our terms and
conditions and on our FAQs. And you can
ask, we got a huge community on uh
Discord, so you can ask anything that
you like. Uh but if you did break the
rules, of course, we will uh uh not pay
for something that broke the rules.
>> Now, I mean, have you ever had to adjust
your rules or or add new rules because
maybe the traders are doing too well on
a certain type of trade? Um I mean, what
are your rules based on? Is it um coming
from a place of because it's based on
the business model we kind of mentioned
before where it depends on that where
you know traders fail or is it coming
from a place of for longer term trading
success? I mean we just want to
understand like like where are the rules
coming from
>> and the the rules comes from risk
management right the that's the first
thing. So the risk managements are of
the business we'll call it right comes
from trading comes from um the
evaluation to see that actually
you know it's not like a one lucky
trader it's actually shows us that you
can um trade right um and show
consistency. This is why for example we
have a rule of um 50% consistency rule
right when your best trade cannot be
responsible to more than 50% of the
target. So of course if you made one
trade and this is on the evaluation
phase on the flex account. Um so if you
made one trade that got you to the
target you didn't prove anything to us.
I cannot categorize you to the profile
that we just talked about by showing me
that you did one trade. So you need to
do your minimum trades are 10 for
example and you have the consistency
rule. Uh we we are changing them and
adopting to the the market conditions or
or our traders conditions. Um, sometimes
it's for uh it will look like it's for
uh bad or or bad better or worse. Uh,
for example, when we first started, you
add 30 days to pass the evaluation. 30
days, that's it. Um, now it's unlimited,
right?
>> Yes.
>> You can take your time. It doesn't
matter if it will take you three three
months or one day. Take your time. Do
your best. So this is a great benefit
for for the traders.
Um we add a 60-second rule before when
you got to stay in that trade for 60
seconds between your entry and your
exit. You got to have at least one
minute um difference. We lowered that
once we checked the data and confirmed
that and the risk uh management allowed
us to do that. We actually lowered that
to 30 seconds. So a lot of sculpers like
that as well because they don't need to
stay a full uh minute in. So we are
adjusting the rules
always trying to help our traders at the
end of the day to pass. Like I said
because we're doing the model of the
hybrid the C uh book which we taking uh
the traders to the market some of our
traders to the market we can adjust it
better and and allow our traders more
flexibility on their trading.
most of us or at least I didn't know
that you have these like you kind of
mentioned it before about these
different categories and you do take
some traders live and and things like
that.
>> You should put that on the website cuz I
think that would really motivate um a
lot of traders to see like where their
trades going, you know, like all the
effort that they're putting into this. I
mean, it could be very motivating. it
basically it is in the FAQs but um but
maybe yeah putting it out there like
>> oh I didn't see okay
>> yeah so people know that hey it's not
just I mean it depends on how you trade
and and if you trade well and and then
you know trade the pool likes the your
strategy you're going to go live you
know um yeah that's that's awesome um
okay I have one more I have another
weird question if more traders ers
become successful at these onlighting
trading prop firms like break the mold
and and it's no longer like the
>> um five only 5% make it and maybe it
becomes 20% or 30%. Do you see that the
online prop trading firms business model
changing?
Um I guess so I mean again we are at the
2025 that passing the evaluation
so and and still good on our risk
management and everything uh around that
but besides that we we are always
looking for
um shifting or or evolving right so for
example one of the one of the things I I
just talked about with Gail the founder
is about offering doing maybe
evaluation, a free evaluation, right?
So, literally give everyone a chance of
joining and and give it a shot, testing
it, see if it's for you, see how you
react to it, because the trading
evaluation gives you
not just the the option to pass to the
funded phase, but also it teaches you a
whole lot about yourself. some of the
some of the Trust Pilot reviews that we
get that the guys are the good ones at
least the the guys are actually becoming
better by learning about themsel and
about how to behave in that market
environment, right?
>> Um so I literally spoke to Gil about it
about opening the doors completely and
giving a free evaluation.
We, like I said, as a business, at least
as I see it, a business got to have a
few streams of income. So, even if we
give the valuation for free, we're still
good on the other side.
>> Yeah, it seems like a win-win situation
overall, whether you're you're a
seasoned trader or a newbie. I think
there's something for everyone through
Trade the Pool really, especially if you
love stocks. um you know there's other
platforms for other types of trading but
you know especially you guys are the
only ones that
um offer stocks is that right? Yeah. And
and it's a a good and a bad thing. Uh on
one end we you know because we are the
only one so no one besides us talks
about it on social media. Right. If you
go to the forex or the future industry
you would find
>> Yeah. Exactly. Everyone is talking about
it. So you need to decide which company
to go to and that's it. On our side we
need to do two things. One uh bring the
awareness and actually tell people about
it. There is, you know, most of the guys
that I'm I'm talking to and tell them
about it, they're their mind is is, you
know, they're losing their mind because
of this the solution that we offer, but
no one's no one's actually knows about
us.
>> They're noticing, right? I find that
really strange. Um,
>> yeah, but I just talked to the um
Bernard Bernardet, if I'm not mistaken,
from Virginia, funded trader. She she
was absolutely sure that most of our
traders our funded traders are actually
from Europe and Asia and and of course
most of our traders are are based in the
US and Canada.
>> Yeah.
>> So she been talking to some of the
traders that she knows from her area and
no one knows about us. So we need to uh
create that awareness and also educate
the guys that come in about prop
trading. what are the rules and how it
works and all of those things. So this
is our um it's good to be alone but on
the other side uh it's good to have more
people that more companies that will
bring that attention as well.
>> Yeah. Um, so there's one thing um I
wanted I think I asked you personally
before because as you know I'm currently
in the evaluation and I'm so happy that
you made um the unlimited time available
unlimited package. So thank you for
doing that um less pressure. So the only
thing um I would love to see and maybe
you might think about doing is copy
trading having multiple accounts. Is
that something that could be on the
horizon soon?
>> Um, yes. So,
right now you can copy uh your trades
between uh two accounts, but the lower
tiers. So, our lower tier is 5K all the
way to 200,000. And we do have a scaling
plan as well. So, you can copy between
the five and the 25, but um you got to
do that manually, right? you you got to
go between the platforms and and
actually click the mouse key. Um what
we're working on right now and probably
by the time and this podcast will be
live um because it's very soon on our
hand um we are creating the copy option
as well. So you will just click the
mouse key and automatically it will go
to those uh trades to those accounts.
>> Oh wow. Yeah,
>> that's awesome.
>> Thank you.
>> It is and and yeah and we bring in two
weeks we will uh launch um also algo
trading as well. So you will be able to
connect your trading
>> algo and set the order for for you know
automatic orders.
>> It's great that you're listening to the
traders and their feedback and and
constantly evolving. I think that's
really important. Um and I have I think
one more question for you. Um you know
Michael uh remember when we were in the
chat with traders trading community uh
two or three years two and a half years
ago and then we were having we were
doing that challenge um the competition
and then you were part of the challenge.
You were also competing you know just to
kind of inspire people and everything as
well. But I noticed you were always like
the in the top five or top 10 like every
day for 21 days. It's like
it it tells me you're a great trader. So
why not just trade for the rest of your
life? I mean, isn't that like what every
dream trader dream a trader would have
is just to trade and do nothing else?
>> That that was definitely my dream uh for
many many years and I achieved that. I
had good very good years that I traded
and did only that even before um going
into the the prop the local prop here um
that I managed the traders there. So I
had a a very good years that I did that
and but for me at least I love to do a
few things that probably interrupt with
that. I still trade these days of course
uh much less than before when I was
actually trading like a one minute every
single day. But I guess uh for me we I
have first of all I really love
innovation. So I always like to invent
something um either technology or a new
evaluation or a new solution or whatever
it is. So, I'm really keen on that and
and the fact that I can, you know, see
it from
see the the behind the scene, see what
the traders are doing, understand how
they operate, um the the new strategies,
the type of risk they putting in, all of
those things by managing this all
operation. It's uh it's really
incredible. Uh I'm still uh pumped by
that even after three years. So, um,
>> yeah.
>> Yeah,
>> actually, I totally understand. I mean
because trading by itself I mean maybe
to some people it's like the best thing
in the world but to me it's it's
challenging but I can see why like um
people who trade even they trade well
and they've been successful they um they
you know they go on to um start
businesses and things like that to to
still be creative to to engage the the
the creative side and things like that.
So I I can I can totally understand
that.
>> And also just to communicate with people
because when you're trading all by
yourself,
>> I had like four years when I literally
just sat and traded by myself, no one
around me, no community, nothing like
that and it and it's obviously super
hard um and lonely. So so it's great to
have we come for example, we come to the
office every day, right?
>> We don't do hybrid or stuff like that.
So there are in the office there are 55
currently 55 um guys that work in so
it's just a bunch of guys talking to
each other laughing brainstorming so so
it's really fun.
>> Yeah that's awesome to hear. Well I know
we're uh up for time but thank you
Michael for coming on to the show and
sharing with us some more of uh your
insights um prop trading in general and
and trade the pool. So, thank you.
>> Happy to be here. Thanks so much.
>> You've reached the end of this episode
of Chat with Traders, but rest assured,
there are more episodes loaded with real
market insight and zero hype on the way
soon. So, to stay updated with each
great new release, subscribe to the
podcast in iTunes. And we'd love it if
you'd leave a rating and review. We'll
catch you next time on Chat with
Traders.
[Music]
What
do you do?